<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>software on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/software/</link>
    <description>Recent content in software on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/software/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>PhD Year 2 Semester 1 Plans</title>
      <link>/post/2020/09/16/phd-year-2-semester-1-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/09/16/phd-year-2-semester-1-plans/</guid>
      <description>The end of summer came crashing in and I find myself starting the second year of the PhD program in Geographical Sciences at the University of Maryland, College Park. For the Fall semester I will be focusing on research and teaching. With Dr. Stewart&amp;rsquo;s guidance I have been able to make substantial progress on the first paper of the dissertation, and I hope to circulate the paper among co-authors in the coming weeks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #11: A conclusion to GSOC!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/08/24/gsoc-blog-11-a-conclusion-to-gsoc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/08/24/gsoc-blog-11-a-conclusion-to-gsoc/</guid>
      <description>A conclusion to Google Summer of Code 2020 A huge thank you to to @sjsrey, @ljwolf, @darribas, @slumnitz, @TaylorOshan, and the larger PySAL group for acting as mentors throughout the summer and welcoming me to the PySAL community. This was a wonderful exercise in developing open-source software and I would highly recommend future students consider contributing to PySAL!
After a summer condensed into ten blog posts we arrive at the finale - one final blog post to mark the end of the program.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #10: Progress on Local Geary</title>
      <link>/post/2020/08/09/gsoc-blog-10-progress-on-local-geary/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/08/09/gsoc-blog-10-progress-on-local-geary/</guid>
      <description>A few brief life updates In a moment typically reserved for &amp;lsquo;As seen on TV ads&amp;hellip;&amp;rsquo;, I knocked over an entire glass of water onto my laptop a few days ago. While the laptop sports one of the new Ryzen 7 8-thread CPUs, the technology remains quite sensitive to water. A nearly-full 8 ounce glass of water came tumbling down on the keyboard. Like most times of brief crisis, I was stunned at what was happening before me.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #7: Midsummer updates</title>
      <link>/post/2020/07/12/gsoc-blog-7-midsummer-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/07/12/gsoc-blog-7-midsummer-updates/</guid>
      <description>Introduction The midpoint of summer is approaching. This coming week will mark a midway point in GSoC2020. As I move away from the hurdle of the last couple of weeks I am setting into a pace of fine-tuning the functions and creating robust notebooks to demonstrate their functionality. While bugs are nuanced errors are sure to arise, I am feeling good about the latter 2/3 of GSoC2020.
Strategy: demonstration notebooks I am working on two &amp;lsquo;final&amp;rsquo; demonstration notebooks that showcase the LOSH and LJC functions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #6: A few good updates</title>
      <link>/post/2020/07/03/gsoc-blog-6-a-few-good-updates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/07/03/gsoc-blog-6-a-few-good-updates/</guid>
      <description>Introduction What a whirlwind of a day to wrap up the week! This was a challenging week for GSoC. As I shared last week, I was feeling a bit down as I had encountered my first major hurdle in the project. This hurdle - inference for Case 1 of Bivariate Local Join Counts - was something that took my about a week of tinkering, reflecting, and trial-and-error to resolve. After an inspiring PySAL developer call I decided to spend the afternoon working on it and a solution finally emerged!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #4 - losh() improvements and local join count inference</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/22/gsoc-blog-4-losh-improvements-and-local-join-count-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/22/gsoc-blog-4-losh-improvements-and-local-join-count-inference/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This has been quite an interesting week in GSoC. I&amp;rsquo;ve made several improvements to the losh() function and have (fingers-crossed) figured out inference for the local join counts! Details below.
losh() improvements As mentioned on the previous blog post, Levi had raised several issues-as-feedback on my GSOC20202 workbook repository. These included:
 Using warnings rather than print statements Simplifying the $VarH_i$ calculation Switching to sparse weights to calculate row sums Breaking notebooks into .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #3 - Working losh() function!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/15/gsoc-blog-3-working-losh-function-and-on-to-local-join-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/15/gsoc-blog-3-working-losh-function-and-on-to-local-join-counts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Slightly shorter blog post this week! More substantial update last week available here. En route to North Carolina to help settle a relative&amp;rsquo;s house. Listening to the audiobook of How To Be An Antiracist by Ibram X. Kendi during the drive.
ESDA call Had a ESDA-specific call with Serge this week on 6/12. We discussed how to fine-tune the LOSH function, which is now mostly operational. The function currently offers chi-square inference (demostration of code available here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #2 - Progress and Revisions</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/07/gsoc-blog-2-coding-progress-revisions-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/07/gsoc-blog-2-coding-progress-revisions-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Coding, Progress, Revisions, and More It has been a few weeks since the last GSoC post (5/22/2020). A lot has happened in the United States during this time, and more is sure to come. In the following post I will share my progress on the project and reflect on the challenges faced so far.
More community bonding The plan of hosting calls on Friday has continued without a hitch. On 5/29 we held a PySAL GSoC-wide call to ask general questions that might pertain to all of the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First GSOC blog post!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/22/first-gsoc-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/22/first-gsoc-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first GSOC blog post! Google Summer of Code (GSOC) 2020 has been going for a couple weeks now and I thought it would be fun to share what progress has been made so far. If you&amp;rsquo;re just joining now you should know that the first month or so is the &amp;lsquo;Community Bonding Period&amp;rsquo;. During this time the student developers get to know their community, establish expectations, and set recurring check-in meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Year 1 Semester 1 Recap</title>
      <link>/post/2020/01/03/phd-year-1-semester-1-recap/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/01/03/phd-year-1-semester-1-recap/</guid>
      <description>What a wild ride this semester has been! It&amp;rsquo;s 2:03AM on 1/3/2020. Considering what has happened in the past two hours, everything I&amp;rsquo;ve done seems a bit trivial. But we press on.
I&amp;rsquo;m most proud of arcospy, a python translation of an existing R package. More info here. The TLDR is that I built a python API that allows users to query the Drug Enforcement Agency (DEA) ARCOS opioid dataset for 2006-2012.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
