<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GSOC on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/gsoc/</link>
    <description>Recent content in GSOC on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gsoc/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #5: The final week of Phase 1!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/29/gsoc-blog-5-the-final-week-of-phase-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/29/gsoc-blog-5-the-final-week-of-phase-1/</guid>
      <description>Introduction We are rapidly heading towards the final week for the first phase of GSoC 2020! What a wild ride it has been - I can&amp;rsquo;t believe it&amp;rsquo;s only been around a month and a half! Brief blog post this week as there is lots to do.
Phase 1 Progress Recap I&amp;rsquo;ve produced solid draft of all of the functions original identified in the proposal, with inference working for nearly all of them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #4 - losh() improvements and local join count inference</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/22/gsoc-blog-4-losh-improvements-and-local-join-count-inference/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/22/gsoc-blog-4-losh-improvements-and-local-join-count-inference/</guid>
      <description>Introduction This has been quite an interesting week in GSoC. I&amp;rsquo;ve made several improvements to the losh() function and have (fingers-crossed) figured out inference for the local join counts! Details below.
losh() improvements As mentioned on the previous blog post, Levi had raised several issues-as-feedback on my GSOC20202 workbook repository. These included:
 Using warnings rather than print statements Simplifying the $VarH_i$ calculation Switching to sparse weights to calculate row sums Breaking notebooks into .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #3 - Working losh() function!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/15/gsoc-blog-3-working-losh-function-and-on-to-local-join-counts/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/15/gsoc-blog-3-working-losh-function-and-on-to-local-join-counts/</guid>
      <description>Introduction Slightly shorter blog post this week! More substantial update last week available here. En route to North Carolina to help settle a relative&amp;rsquo;s house. Listening to the audiobook of How To Be An Antiracist by Ibram X. Kendi during the drive.
ESDA call Had a ESDA-specific call with Serge this week on 6/12. We discussed how to fine-tune the LOSH function, which is now mostly operational. The function currently offers chi-square inference (demostration of code available here).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GSOC Blog #2 - Progress and Revisions</title>
      <link>/post/2020/06/07/gsoc-blog-2-coding-progress-revisions-and-more/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/06/07/gsoc-blog-2-coding-progress-revisions-and-more/</guid>
      <description>Coding, Progress, Revisions, and More It has been a few weeks since the last GSoC post (5/22/2020). A lot has happened in the United States during this time, and more is sure to come. In the following post I will share my progress on the project and reflect on the challenges faced so far.
More community bonding The plan of hosting calls on Friday has continued without a hitch. On 5/29 we held a PySAL GSoC-wide call to ask general questions that might pertain to all of the projects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First GSOC blog post!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/22/first-gsoc-blog-post/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/22/first-gsoc-blog-post/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my first GSOC blog post! Google Summer of Code (GSOC) 2020 has been going for a couple weeks now and I thought it would be fun to share what progress has been made so far. If you&amp;rsquo;re just joining now you should know that the first month or so is the &amp;lsquo;Community Bonding Period&amp;rsquo;. During this time the student developers get to know their community, establish expectations, and set recurring check-in meetings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD Year 1 Semester 2 Recap and Summer Plans</title>
      <link>/post/2020/05/09/phd-year-1-semester-2-recap-and-summer-plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/05/09/phd-year-1-semester-2-recap-and-summer-plans/</guid>
      <description>Going to keep this update brief as I will be doing a lot more blogging this summer (more on that later)! This semester was incredibly challenging. Probably the hardest semester of work and school I have ever countered. Yet as things in life tend to do, everything came together at the finish line. Class projects, research expectations, and personal goals.
I completed the first stage in the doctoral process at UMD - the Comprehensive Portfolio.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>