<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on A minimal Hugo website</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on A minimal Hugo website</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Spatial weight matrices from R (or other programs!) into SAS</title>
      <link>/post/2021/01/14/loading-spatial-weight-matrices-into-sas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2021/01/14/loading-spatial-weight-matrices-into-sas/</guid>
      <description>In some recent research efforts I was attempting to deploy a specific type of spatial model in R. This spatial model has many names including a cross-regressive model, the spatially-lagged X model, or, more simply, the SLX model. You can spot this model whenever you see the inclusion of a spatial weights matrix on an X variable in the right hand side of the regression equation. For example, take a simple linear regression:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>arcos and arcospy now in JOSS!</title>
      <link>/post/2020/09/30/arcos-and-arcospy-now-in-joss/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Sep 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/2020/09/30/arcos-and-arcospy-now-in-joss/</guid>
      <description>Just a short post to announce a milestone in the arcos and arcospy journey! A writeup of the software was accepted at The Journal of Open Source Software. The paper is available online here. This was quite the adventure, and I thought it would be fun to quickly lay out the major moments leading up to this point.
 Summer 2019: I read a Washington Post story about the release of a large portion of the ARCOS database and an accompanying software package to access the data called arcos.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
